<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Productivity on 🙈   🙉</title>
    <link>https://blog.stefanaleksic.com/tags/productivity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Productivity on 🙈   🙉</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2018 01:30:00 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.stefanaleksic.com/tags/productivity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Live Streaming with Mac</title>
      <link>https://blog.stefanaleksic.com/posts/2018/04/17/obs_mac/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2018 01:30:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.stefanaleksic.com/posts/2018/04/17/obs_mac/</guid>
      <description>I recently started live streaming my studying using Mac and Open Broadcaster Software (OBS)
In this blog post, I want to talk about how I use OBS and other tools to create an effective and engaging live streaming experience.
Live streaming your computer screen has historically had a gaming connotation. Because of this, most streaming tools have been focused on the Windows operating system. This has left a giant void in support of Mac and Linux.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cool Hacker Tools -- Git</title>
      <link>https://blog.stefanaleksic.com/posts/2018/04/08/git/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2018 01:30:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.stefanaleksic.com/posts/2018/04/08/git/</guid>
      <description>This blog post series’ goal is to provide a comprehensive list of tools I use and how to set them up.
When I first started programming, I was so curious to try the coolest gadgets and try new editors, window managers, and programming languages. This blog post’s goal is to try to share as much information that I have with you, either a complete beginner, looking to increase your productivity and to make your stuff look really cool, or an experienced developer looking to add a few tools to your arsenal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should Fish Have Twitter Accounts: Thinking about Questions and Ideas</title>
      <link>https://blog.stefanaleksic.com/posts/2019/03/20/time/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2018 01:30:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.stefanaleksic.com/posts/2019/03/20/time/</guid>
      <description>Answering specific questions is so limiting that when someone asks me to take part in answering a question they ask, I refuse. Usually, this would make a person anti-social, and make them lose all their friends. However, I&amp;rsquo;ve devised a system that works really well to avoid answering specific questions that don&amp;rsquo;t have a lot of practicality for anything other than their own domain.
Instead of answering a specific question, I like to try to abstract away the specificity and go for the root of the question.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cool Hacker Tools -- Vim</title>
      <link>https://blog.stefanaleksic.com/posts/2018/03/23/cool_hacker_tools_part_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 01:30:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.stefanaleksic.com/posts/2018/03/23/cool_hacker_tools_part_1/</guid>
      <description>This blog post series&amp;rsquo; goal is to provide a comprehensive list of tools I use and how to set them up.
When I first started programming, I was so curious to try the coolest gadgets and try new editors, window managers, and programming languages. This blog post’s goal is to try to share as much information that I have with you, either a complete beginner, looking to increase your productivity and to make your stuff look really cool, or an experienced developer looking to add a few tools to your arsenal.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>