<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Uncategorized on 🙈   🙉</title>
    <link>https://blog.stefanaleksic.com/tags/uncategorized/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Uncategorized on 🙈   🙉</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2018 01:30:00 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.stefanaleksic.com/tags/uncategorized/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>That Took a While</title>
      <link>https://blog.stefanaleksic.com/posts/2018/03/22/that_took_a_while/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2018 01:30:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.stefanaleksic.com/posts/2018/03/22/that_took_a_while/</guid>
      <description>I finally have my own hosted blog! Picking a good enough Hugo theme was so incredibly difficult, but at least for right now, I picked the hugo-zen theme. There were a few issues I found with it so I modified it a bunch. But as a foundation, I&amp;rsquo;ve found it to be very good.
I wanted to add my own flavor to it so I added a glitch art image and changed the coloring a bit to match it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sleeping on the Floor</title>
      <link>https://blog.stefanaleksic.com/posts/2017/12/31/floor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2017 01:30:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.stefanaleksic.com/posts/2017/12/31/floor/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been sleeping on the floor for the past 3 months, it has been nothing short of amazing.
When I moved to my new room in San Francisco, I found out the previous tenant never took their mattress with them. They left it there for some reason. I needed a bed so I bought some queen sized bed sheets and a pillow that I put on the mattress lying on my floor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Today was a Good Day</title>
      <link>https://blog.stefanaleksic.com/posts/2017/12/18/good_day/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 01:30:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.stefanaleksic.com/posts/2017/12/18/good_day/</guid>
      <description>I had a fantastic day and wanted to write about it.
My friend Jeron came to SF to hang out for the weekend. I woke up, got ready for the day, and got a text message from my roommate, Dan, asking if we want to get brunch. I don’t know why he even asks me anymore when I always say yes. I was so excited and hungry. I called my friend Changbai to ask if he wanted to join us at The Grove in Hayes Valley.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick Serbian Lesson — Kako Da Ne</title>
      <link>https://blog.stefanaleksic.com/posts/2016/11/01/kako_da_ne/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 01:30:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.stefanaleksic.com/posts/2016/11/01/kako_da_ne/</guid>
      <description>Why do so many Serbian people keep on saying “How yes no” in regular conversation?
When trying to translate “kako da ne” into English, Google picks it up as Croatian and gives the incorrect translation of “how yes no.”
Како да не.
This translates to two completely different phrases given a different tone.
When used in a sarcastic way, it means “yeah, ok” or “yeah, right.” Used in a non sarcastic tone it means “of course” which might be a bit strange at first to someone learning Serbian.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slavic Antithesis</title>
      <link>https://blog.stefanaleksic.com/posts/2016/11/01/antithesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 01:30:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.stefanaleksic.com/posts/2016/11/01/antithesis/</guid>
      <description>Look up in the sky! It’s a bird! It’s a plane! No! It’s Superman!
The Slavic Antithesis is used in South-Slavic epic poetry. Serbian, Bosnian, Croatian, Macedonian, etc. It’s a fascinating literary stylistic device in which the author poses a question, gives a number of incorrect answers, and finally gives the correct answer. This increases the validity as well as the impact of the last answer.
An Example “Šta se bijeli u gori zelenoj?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who</title>
      <link>https://blog.stefanaleksic.com/posts/2016/08/08/who/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2016 01:30:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.stefanaleksic.com/posts/2016/08/08/who/</guid>
      <description>I went to an art workshop last week. It was hosted by an Austrian artist couple who call themselves UBERMORGEN. If I never knew anything about them, or if I never heard of their art, I would think that they were hackers making cool side projects for fun. I would never view them as artists. Look at their projects and tell me they wouldn’t win 1st place at any hackathon with those ideas.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>